In this video, I'm going to break down
exactly how I set up Facebook ads for
contractors and construction companies.
With everything that's working in 2025,
I'll be building out a demonstration ad
campaign so you can see the type of
images that are working right now, as
well as the actual ad copy that
persuades the people to book in a call
and get that estimate. So, make sure you
stick around and watch the whole video
so you don't miss out on anything
important. But, there's one thing that I
don't want to do, and it's waste any
more of your time. So, let's just jump
straight into Facebook ads and teach you
exactly how to set this up for your
business. The first thing we want to do
is head over to ads manager and make
sure you're in the campaigns area and
then tap on create. The type of campaign
objective that we want is leads because
we want people to fill out our website
form or the instant form that we create
here because we want all their details
so we can give them a quote. But once
you've selected it, just go and
continue. The type of campaign that
we're going to be building out today is
going to be a bathroom remodeling
campaign. So, I'm just going to label
the campaign bathroom remodeling because
that's the exact campaign that we're
building out. So, this strategy that I'm
going to teach you works insanely well
for all different contractors and
construction companies. So, don't stress
if you're not a bathroom remodeling
company. This is just purely an example.
This strategy just works insanely well
for any type of service-based businesses
that works for homeowners doing
residential work. So, if you're not a
bathroom remodeling service, but you
still service homeowners, these ads will
still work insanely well for you. But
what we want to do now is just set in
the budget. I would personally go around
50 to $100 per day. Now that's in
Australian dollars. So it's about 35
to75 USD or 25 to50 if you live in the
UK. So I'm just changing this over to 50
right now. And for the campaign area, we
don't really need to stress about
anything else. So we just tap on next.
Now for the conversion location, this is
where you pick where you want the
conversion to happen. So if you want
them to fill out the form on your
website, you can put in your website
link here. or if you want them to fill
out an instant form through Facebook,
which is what I personally recommend
because it doesn't take them out of
Facebook. It's a lot easier, quicker
load times and everything like that.
What you want to do is you just go down
to here and then tap on single and go
straight to instant forms. I personally
believe that these work best. And then
you just want to pick your Facebook page
here. I just picked my demonstration ad
account. Now, the performance goal, we
want to focus on maximize number of
leads, not maximize number of conversion
leads. Now, I know you're probably
thinking that this will be a lot better
getting maximized number of conversion
leads because the clients are more
conversion focused. That's not the case.
I've been spending thousands of dollars
on Facebook ads for years and they
brought this in and I've tested it with
tens of thousands of dollars and it
hasn't really changed the results at
all. The things that do change the
results is having a high intent form.
So, having multiple questions on your
instant form or your website form to
make sure that the lead is high quality.
If you have it on maximize number of
conversion leads, you end up just kind
of paying a premium price for the same
audience anyway. So, I personally
recommend to just stay with the
maximized number of leads. That's how I
set it up. But after you've done that,
we're just going to go down to the
actual location audience. Now, as you
can tell, I'm Australian. And if you're
watching this from any other place like
the UK, United States, or anything like
that, these ads still work insanely well
for you. Majority of my clients are from
the US and UK. So, this strategy was
literally handcrafted by those
audiences. but it also does work
insanely well in Australia as well. So
for locations, we just want to tap on
the little pencil here, tap this little
arrow down here, and just type in your
town or suburb. So it takes you directly
to it. So for me, I'm just going to type
in Chadston, and it's going to take me
directly here. And then for the
targeting, what we want to do is just
tap on drop pin and just drop a pin like
that. And then we can increase or
decrease our service location. So just
say we service 20 mi around here. But
there is still one thing you need to do
here and it's excluding the areas around
where you target because Facebook
sometimes trickles your ad spends into
areas that you don't service and you end
up just wasting money on getting leads
and jobs that you can't actually service
because they're too far away. So to stop
that, what you want to do is tap on drop
pin again and just drop it around your
circle and let me just increase this a
slight bit. Now we just want to tap on
it again. Tap on it here and then tap on
exclude. Now this whole area here is
excluded. Now, you just want to do this
all around the circle. Now, I hope
you're enjoying the value that I'm
giving you in this video. I do have a
full marketing course right below this
video where I teach you Facebook ads,
Google ads, and exactly how to automate
your business. If you are interested in
that, there's a link right below in the
description. Go check it out. But
without further ado, let's just jump
straight in the video and continue
giving you that value. Now, obviously,
since this is a demonstration account,
I'm not going to waste my time building
out all the exclusions all around this.
But to sum it all up, I would just put
exclusion circles like this all around
the actual blue circle. So this way ad
spend doesn't trickle off into any of
the areas around it. You don't need to
worry about too far away like over here
because Facebook ads isn't going to
accidentally send a couple of ads over
here. But once you've done all that, you
just want to scroll down and you don't
need to worry about suggesting an
audience or including any of these
custom audiences or anything like that
unless you're doing a retargeting
campaign, which in this example we're
not. Just tap on next. And now we're
directly in the actual ad level. So this
is where the money gets made. This is
the exact thing that people see and the
form that they fill out to get a quote
from you. This bit needs to be on point.
Now, what I personally like to do is set
up single image ads. You can also do
video ads. They work extremely well. But
if you want to do mass testing and get
results as fast as possible, single
image ads are usually the best just
because you can test a ridiculous amount
of them fast as possible without having
to worry about editing videos, putting
in captions, and actually creating the
video itself. So, I'm just going to
select single image or video and then
we're going to go down and set up our
creative. So, we're going to tap on
image ad. Now, just ignore the rest of
these. These are just different ad
demonstrations that I've created for my
other tutorials. But as you can see
here, there's a junk removal, house
washing, landscaping, handyman services,
and this is the one that we're going
with right now, which is for a bathroom
remodeling service. If you can see with
all the images that I use, there's
something in common, and they're all
very personal images showing the actual
business owner or the work crew. The
reason why I do this is because it just
makes it very genuine and looks either
like a profile picture or just a local
post in the community, which is exactly
what you want because you want people to
see you and know who they're going to be
dealing with when they pick up that
phone and call you or fill out the form.
Having those personal photos in there
just builds that trust instantly. Now,
for the primary text and everything like
that, I'm not going to build this in
this area just because it looks ugly and
you can't really see what I'm doing. So,
just wait around. I'm going to be
building that right after this. So,
let's just tap on next for right now.
Now, here's some different AI
generations. Honestly, some of these
actually work really well. So, let's
just tap ones that are relevant to us.
So, as you can see here, there's a
little bit of construction in the
background. So, that kind of suits our
type of ad. Now, if this was a bathroom
background, I'd probably click on it,
but it's not. But, if there is anything
good, you can always just tap on it
here. But, we're just going to skip and
continue. Now, the type of enhancements
that you want on your ads is we don't
want to bother with flex media, enhanced
CTA, or add animation. And we definitely
don't want text improvements either. So,
we just want to have add music, visual
touch-ups, and ad overlays. Now, tap on
done. All right. So, this is what our ad
is looking like right now. Just the
absolute bare bones, just a photo with a
little bit of social proof. Now, scroll
down and let's actually fill out the
primary text. So, this is at the very
top of the ad. And this is kind of where
you do most of the selling. The image is
for stopping the scroll. And then the
primary text is for really selling the
person on it. And the headline is mainly
just a call to action and to reaffirm
what your service is. So, here is the
primary text that I'm going with. It's
big. It's long. It's very genuine. Like
I said, it's very similar to a local
notice board post, like a local
community member reaching out to their
fellow neighbors. That's exactly what I
want. That's why I bring out the hello
neighbors at the very top to make it as
friendly as possible. But here's the ad
copy. You can steal it if you want and
just copy and paste it and change it
around to your business. But this is
also what it looks like when you tap on
see more. So, it's just this big ad copy
here. Now, some people like to have very
small ad copy, just super punchy, but
I've been running ads for a very long
time, and that's just not the best way
to go about it, right? You have one time
on selling this person to click on your
ad and get a quote. So, you want to do
as much as possible to actually persuade
them to trust you enough to come through
and get that quote from you because
they're making a big investment to you,
whether it's getting their roof
repaired, getting their bathroom
remodeled, or just any other service
like that. So, you just need to build
that trust as fast as possible. It also
works insanely well because not many
people run ads like this. A lot of
people just run ads that's like, "Want
your bathroom remodeled? Get your free
quote. Here's some benefits of us.
Satisfaction guarantee, call to action,
and urgency." That's just the main
things they put in a very short blur.
And it just doesn't really help persuade
them because every single one of those
company ads look the exact same where
this one sticks out like a sore thumb
because right off the bat, it's super
genuine and it kind of looks like a
profile picture. So, it stops the scroll
instantly. People are used to seeing ads
of before and after photos of a
remodeled bathroom or anything like
that. They just don't care. The thing
that really sells people is people.
Remember this quote, people buy from
people. So, just be a person. Don't be a
company. Now, let's go down to the
actual headline. And the headline is
super simple. You just tell them what
you want them to do. So, if it's get
your free quote, just put in get your
free quote or get your bathroom remodel.
Just anything like that. So, I just went
with a super bare bones headline right
here. If you do have a discount or
anything like that, you can put in a
discount like 20% off or anything. But
I'm not a massive fan of using price to
get leads because that just means you're
just going to get a lot more cheaper
people than the pricier people that you
probably want to be hiring you. So for
the description, you just want to put in
social proof like how many testimonials
you have, how many jobs you completed,
just anything like that to really push
that trust. So for this example, we're
just going to do over 350 completed
jobs. So to really just push the fact
that we're a big business and we've done
a lot of bathroom renovations. So as you
can see here, this just appears right
below the call to action. I usually
would go with Google reviews if I didn't
have the actual Google reviews put on
the photo. But then we want to change
the call to action button to get quote
because we want people to tap on it and
get a quote from. And as you can see
here, the ad is actually done. Now you
can see the different previews of it.
This is what it looks like on Facebook.
Now obviously it's run through my
demonstration account. It would look a
lot better if it was through CM
Constructions. But these are the exact
style of ads that are working really
well in 2025, which is just those
personal genuine ads. The ones that
don't look like some massive company.
They just look like a genuine group of
real people that you can trust. But
we're not done just yet. We still need
to actually create the instant form for
any of the people that aren't using
their website to get the leads. So,
scroll down to destination. Just tap on
create form. I'm going to teach you the
best way to set up your instant form so
you don't have to worry about tire
kicker leads. So, we want to start this
off on more volume and we want to have
this as open. Then we're going to tap on
next. We're going to remove our greeting
because it's just a bit of wasted time.
And then we're going to tap on next.
Again, what we want to do is ask
multiple questions here. So, asking
things like their best contact method,
whether it's phone number, email, SMS,
or how urgently they need it done, or
just anything else related to your
particular service. So, how you do this
here is you just tap on add question,
and you can add in a multiple choice
question or short answers. I personally
mainly use multiple choice questions,
but either is fine. The golden area is
around three to four different
questions. But once you put in that, you
just want to go down here and make sure
you're grabbing the right details, which
is their full name, email address, phone
number, and probably their street
address as well, which you can just grab
in here like this. And then what you
want to do is just tap on next again.
And now we're going to fill out our
privacy policy. You can just link your
website in here, or you can actually
create a privacy policy in Google Docs.
They're super easy to set up. It's
basically you just saying that you're
not going to sell their information to
anybody. Once you've done that, tap on
next. And you just want to have a nice
little headline like, "Thanks, you're
all set." And a description telling them
how soon they're probably going to
receive their quote. So, you receive
your quote in the next 24 to 48 hours or
we're going to call you within the next
24 to 48 hours to arrange it. Or just
anything like that. And then for the
additional action, I personally like to
have this as call business. So, this is
the button right at the bottom of their
page where they can just call you
straight away if they need you urgently.
All right. Well, that's it for the
video. But if you do want that unfair
advantage of your competitors so you can
really dominate your area and understand
the things that I can't share for free
on YouTube, there's a link in the
description to my home service marketing
course. I'll teach you everything from
Facebook ads, Google ads to automating
your whole entire business so you can
sit back, relax, crack a beer, and have
leads coming in 24/7. So, if you're that
type of business owner that just wants
to fast track the results as fast as
possible, not waste any time doing trial
and error and testing multiple different
ads, go check out my course and
community. You can even talk to me
directly there if you need some more
personal help. And I do not charge for
the personal help.